THE ELUSIVE
SAMURAI
-Is this the way?
-Yes.
If we cross the ridge, we'll come across
the road the enemies withdrew from.
Oh, my gosh! I just ate a spider's web.
-Don't be so loud.
-Lord Tokiyuki.
Gross.
How do you feel now that you've had
your first victorious battle?
I guess it was my first battle.
I was just focused on running,
and before I knew it,
the enemy's head was right in front of me.
I…
I want to say thank you.
Don't mention it!
There are conditions to winning a war
by way of the game of tag.
First, you must be
a valuable leader in battle,
which means you will become
the top target.
Second, you must have trustworthy
retainers who'll act as your weapons.
In order to fulfill these two conditions,
you must not forget your pride
as a Hojo orphan.
And you must be a boy of character
who people will be drawn to.
If you do those two things,
one day, you can defeat any demon
in the game of tag.
I understand.
I swear to return here.
And defeat Ashikaga,
who caused all the turmoil!
You are heroic.
And also, I saw another vision
a moment ago.
I saw that something terrible would happen
if you throw that sword from there.
-Uh-oh.
-My lord!
Be careful! Get back!
Tokiyuki narrowly escaped
a ruined Kamakura.
For someone of such small stature,
he has such a grand fate awaiting him.
The boy who will later shake the country
begins his growth in his new world.
However…
Good morning, Lord Tokiyuki.
You're looking quite good for someone
who was running around all day yesterday.
Mr. Yorishige! What is this inappropriate
atmosphere with the shrine maidens?
Lord Tokiyuki, try a locust!
I appointed them to bring you breakfast
and physical contact
to warm your grieving heart!
And what do you make of this?
As you can see,
I've dug a hole to trap you.
I saw a future where you were
running down this road to get away!
Since this place is filled
with divine energy,
-it gives me a boost of holy power…
-He said he saw a vision.
He's still speaking like a sham.
Which means--
No matter where you run off to,
I'll know right away.
You see, this is my backyard. My domain!
Behold, this is the Suwa Grand Shrine!
Now.
Come now, let's start your martial
and academic arts training.
ANCIENT COURT
AND MILITARY PRACTICES
But I'm still acclimating.
The boy who symbolizes
Kamakura shogunate's restoration
has no time to waste!
All right, take two! A "running gag" is
a word I learned from the future.
But repeating the same joke
a third time won't work.
I don't care. Let me out!
I'm sorry, Lord Tokiyuki.
Father is always like this,
-forcing things along on his own terms.
-What's this?
He often behaves in eccentric ways,
-and he goes on about nonsense.
-Roast deer over rice?
Shizuku, I think I found something tasty.
But he means well, so don't worry.
How can I not worry hearing that?
Father, why would you dig a hole
in the road leading to the shrine?
-I'm sorry.
-I'm grateful to this man
for saving my life,
but does he have
any realistic plans for what's to come?
Suwa Shrine is so much smaller
than Tsurugaoka Hachimangu Shrine,
so it's hard to believe
that the priest of this shrine
can help me take back Kamakura
and defeat Takauji Ashikaga.
SEVERAL DAYS LATER
I can't believe he doesn't get tired
of running away so much day after day.
Ugh, I'm tired of digging holes.
That Young Lord… Isn't he spoiled,
being the heir to the shogunate?
Maybe he learned to run away
from everything.
You're wrong.
At his core, he's honest and earnest.
But he has never understood
the reason to study diligently
because he was raised
to be a puppet ruler.
He's never had any
meaningful goals in his life.
If anything, I'm the one who's lacking.
I haven't proven to him yet
whether I have the power
to help him reach his goals!
No one will think I'll run away
on a day like this.
Learning the art of war today? It seems
most useless for someone like me.
Oh, come on.
I don't need to study.
I'll do what you want.
All I need to do is run around
the battlefield, right?
Even while your army is losing!
Lord Tokiyuki,
I promise to God, I cannot lose.
You know why?
Because I am a true god.
This rain is in the way.
I need to show you something.
Now…
I'll clear the clouds.
Hip, hip…
Hooray!
Amazing!
The Suwa Sect is composed of warriors
who believe in Suwa Myojin,
and they are proud of their strength
and iron unity under their faith in me.
Was I able to convince you?
There is a god looking after you.
10,000 men on horseback
at one call from god.
If you acquire the qualities of a hero,
it would mean an alliance
between a hero and a god.
And even more soldiers will
join us tenfold!
So what shall we do today?
I'll go to my desk and study.
That's what I wanted to hear!
-Your aged cheek is surprisingly…
-You adorable thing.
-…like a nail file!
-Rub, rub, rub, rub, rub, rub!
I think I'll trust him.
I think he'll make me a hero
like he predicted.
I've got those words out of him.
Everyone, you're welcome to go home!
* TOKIYUKI
That was rough in the rain.
Hey, where'd the enthusiasm go? Come on!
Well, they're not
always that energetic, you see.
Come on, let's knock out the studying.
-You know a warrior can't lie! Come on.
-You tricked me!
-Yorishige Suwa understood Tokiyuki best…
-Let's get started.
…and managed to enlighten him
on his future.
In just a short while,
he had an immeasurable impact.
And now,
the hero hatchling begins to quietly
sharpen his fang in the arms of a god.
What a clean fall!
Shut up!
It looks like you're getting used to
life in Suwa.
Now, it's time to gain some allies.
Let's gather retainers just for you.
-Yes.
Retainers.
WHAT ARE "RETAINERS"?
Yes. Retainers are vassals that form
a master-and-servant relationship
with their potent military commander.
And they risk their lives
fighting for him.
It wouldn't be an exaggeration to say that
the strength of the retainers
is the strength of the lord.
Because you've tragically lost
your close family and retainers,
you must rebuild from nothing.
Allow me to introduce them again!
Kojiro is the greatest swordsman
of your generation.
And one day he will lead
as your military commander.
Sup, Young Lord.
Ayako has unrivaled physical strength
and is brimming with artistic talent.
She remains a lady even in battle.
Young Lord!
Shizuku is attentive
and versed in several secret arts.
As a servant, she takes care of
the general affairs at home.
These three are your age,
but I know you can count on them.
First, get to know them well,
and show that you know
how to utilize their skills.
If you all grow up together, like family,
then eventually you will have
tight-knit, reliable retainers.
And in the future, we'll recruit
more talent as we come across them.
The number of your retainers
is sure to grow!
In the future, this is what they call
a hero's journey.
Who cares?
Right, then, what shall I do, my lord?
I'll do anything you ask.
Anything?
Of course. We're retainers!
Then let's play tag!
Oh, not that.
Instant rejection!
My lord, once you start running,
you go far into the horizon.
YAY
Right? In a way, it's amazing
how much energy you have to run.
If we're gonna do something fun,
let's sneak into the samurai's houses,
the ones that betrayed you for Ashikaga.
Then we'll all take a dump
and rub it in everywhere.
How crass!
-Let's do push-ups till someone gives up!
-That sounds like hell!
I want to see how many marbles will fit
in an ants' nest.
What's wrong with you?
-What is wrong with…
-One, two…
…my retainers?
Young Lord, how about we go hunting?
It's fun and it'll be good training.
Are those of the shrine allowed
to kill animals?
It's okay.
Suwa Myojin is also a God of Hunting.
Unlike other Shinto sects,
we hunt and eat like crazy.
What a strange god.
Lord Yorishige.
It seems Lord Tokiyuki's group
has gone hunting.
I saw that.
I saw the tribulations they'll face too.
Surprise!
-Wow. Close one. By your standards.
-What do you mean "by your standards"?
It's hard to see through the foliage here.
Wow!
Here, my lord! One more time.
Found you!
Dang, Mr. Rabbit is fast.
She's a monster.
Right? I've seen her turn rabbits
into red mist plenty of times.
Wait!
What is that beast?
It was rumored in the neighboring province
that there's a huge
flesh-eating Ox Demon in these hills.
Lord Tokiyuki,
your adversary is a man
who subjugates far more ferocious beasts.
Show me how you can combine
strength with your allies
to splendidly take down this beast.
NANBOKUCHO GAME OF TAG
OX DEMON BOTAN
It won't even pierce its skin.
Retreat! Retreat to higher ground!
We can't defeat it
with just the two of us.
We will guide the Young Lord while we run.
Okay!
No, we can defeat it.
-Shizuku!
-Since when did you get to safety?
Kojiro, Aya,
it's not just you two anymore.
We have Lord Tokiyuki.
Me?
CURRENT LOCATION
Lord Tokiyuki, you evade the beast
while leading it to the larch.
DESTINATION
While you do that,
Kojiro and Aya will wait for it there.
You two already know, right?
What's under the tree.
-Yes.
All right, my lord.
Till then, it's all yours!
Hey, wait! What do you mean it's all mine?
And you want me to lead it
while dodging it?
That's insane!
What kind of retainer makes their lord be
a part of this sort of plan!
He says that, but he's evading
in ungodly rapid succession!
Looking good!
Our lord has an astounding talent
in dodging.
Let's fine-tune it!
It's ready!
-Straight under the tree!
-All right!
Hey! What am I supposed to do with it now?
Come on, you swine,
for baring your fangs
at Tokiyuki Hojo's party,
I'll make sure you regret it.
Neither arrow nor sword could hurt you.
You wouldn't die
even if you fell off a cliff.
I'm sorry,
but what awaits you there
is the blade of god.
The water feels just right.
Hot springs are a Suwa specialty!
Good heavens.
-Yay!
-We killed the beast in no time.
-That was hard.
I want to butcher and eat it…
Once we saw the bow wasn't effective,
we figured out how
to work with each other's
individual strengths.
We used our resourcefulness
to our advantage,
and didn't hesitate
to deal with this unknown monster.
Young Lord! Let's go to the spring!
But what was this beast?
It was probably a beast
remaining from ancient times.
It didn't even have family
to bear offspring.
If there were others of its kind,
it probably wouldn't have fallen
under the influence of evil.
From now on,
let's conduct Tokiyuki party's
strategic meetings in the hot springs!
I like that!
I'm going to bring ice
from the ice chamber
and some mandarin juice.
You know, "Tokiyuki Party"
is too obvious to enemies.
Let's think of something more vague!
Let's see…
Since we're a party that uses
our lord's "running" as its main tactic,
"Wrap Up Your Tail and Flee Party"!
Lame!
-Sweet-tooth Party!
-Definitely not!
Born to Runner Up Party.
I don't think that's good?
-Loser's Pick Party!
-That hurts!
Flighting Escaping Just Run Party!
That's so long!
-Although I've lost everything…
-Hi-yah!
…they cheer me up
by treating me like a friend.
And still, they don't forget
that I'm their lord.
I know!
What about "the Elusive Warriors"?
How'd you come up with that?
Because we are warriors
for an elusive lord!
Yes. The Elusive Warriors. That's good.
These retainers are too good for me.
Let's all grow strong together
in this land!
Now, let's eat
the good parts of that beast first.
We'll tell Lord Yorishige about it after.
What?
What the…
Why did you eat our whole catch,
you dumb god!
It was a pitiful beast
that fell to the influence of evil!
I'm purifying its soul
in my sacred stomach.
BEAST THAT'S STRANGE TO ME
WILL WANDER IN GLOOMY DARKNESS
-Shut up! Give me back my meat!
-You're a gluttonous god!
REJECTED
What is going on in this god's stomach?
I see.
I can see it.
Yorishige of Suwa is plotting
something wicked.
I'll never let him get away with it.
EPISODE 4 (YEAR OF 1333):
SADAMUNE APPEARS!
Let's go!